totalmotorcycle.com 2019-04-06

# Privacy Policy • Total Motorcycle

## **_[](https://www.totalmotorcycle.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/TMWemaillogo-2015a.jpg)_**

## Privacy Policy – The Advanced Version

## Privacy Policy – The Basic Version

## Who we are

Our website address is: [https://www.totalmotorcycle.com](https://www.totalmotorcycle.com/).

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

Visitors are not given the option to leave comments on the main website, therefore, no personal data is collected.

### Media

Visitors are not given the option to upload media to the main website, therefore, no personal data is collected.

### Contact forms

Your personal contact information (name, email address) will only be used by us to correspond with you on a specific matter that you reach out to us for, and it will be deleted by us after completing our correspondence. We never keep, sell, or use your personal information for any other purpose.

To contact us, please use our [Contact Us](https://www.totalmotorcycle.com/contactus) form in the footer on all pages across the main website.

### Cookies

The forum is based on phpBB software and uses three cookies for Visitors. The first two cookies just contain a user identifier (user ID) and an anonymous session identifier (session ID), automatically assigned to you by the phpBB software. A third cookie will be created once you have browsed topics within the forums and is used to store which topics have been read, thereby improving your user experience.  If you are a Member (registered user), an additional cookie will be placed on your computer if you select the box “Remember Me” when logging in.  These minimal cookies are required for the operation of the phpBB forum.

The main site does not use cookies for regular Visitors, only for staff members with login credentials. When staff members log in, we will set up several cookies to save their login information and screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If they select “Remember Me”, their login will persist for two weeks. If they log out of their account, the login cookies will be removed. If staff members edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in their browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article they just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Some of our advertising is provided through contracts we have with individual companies to provide direct advertising. We also work with the following third party advertisers, who collect non-personal and non-identifying information.  These third parties also have their own opt-out and privacy policies, linked here for your reference:

### Analytics

The only authorized services collecting website analytics are Google Analytics and Ezoic. The user analytics we are provided from these services are non-identifiable and contain no personal information. We use these analytics to improve the user experience on our website and never sell the analytics data to third parties.

### Forums

We deploy a phpBB forum for visitors with mutual interest to interact.  Non-members (“Visitors”) can search and read forum articles without logging in. Registered users (“Members”) must have an account. Members must sign up with a unique username, password, and unique, verified email address. Members must also accept the forum terms and conditions to create an account.  Here is the link to the [forum terms and conditions](https://www.totalmotorcycle.com/BBS/ucp.php?mode=terms).

On the forums, we collect your personal information via one of two ways. The first is through cookies; please see the Cookies section contained in this Privacy Policy for more information. The second way in which we collect your information is by what you submit to us. This can be, and is not limited to: posting as an anonymous user, registering for an account, and posts submitted by you after registration and whilst logged in.

Your account will at a bare minimum contain a uniquely identifiable name, a personal password used for logging into your account and a personal, valid email address. Your information for your account is protected by data-protection laws applicable in the country that hosts us. Any information beyond your user name, your password, and your email address required by us during the registration process is either mandatory or optional, at our discretion. In all cases, you have the option of what information in your account is publicly displayed. Furthermore, within your account, you have the option to opt-in or opt-out of automatically generated emails from the phpBB software.

Your password is ciphered (a one-way hash) so that it is secure. However, it is recommended that you do not reuse the same password across a number of different websites. Your password is the means of accessing your account, so please guard it carefully and under no circumstance will anyone affiliated with us, phpBB or another 3rd party, legitimately ask you for your password. Should you forget your password for your account, you can use the “I forgot my password” feature provided by the phpBB software. This process will ask you to submit your user name and your email, then the phpBB software will generate a new password to reclaim your account.

Members can choose to share other personal information such as name, location, age, birth date, motorcycle model owned, and years of riding experience, which will be able to be viewed by members and visitors.  Members may choose to leave these fields blank and/or edit them at any time.

For operation of the forum, IP address and email address of each member is stored in clear text. For each separate posting, the member’s IP address is stored in clear text.

The forum member list is available to any registered member, however, the only information displayed in the member list is username, number of posts, website (if provided by user), join date, and last active date.

Any member, when logged in, can click on the username of any other member.  Information that was entered by the other member such as age, sex, location, interests, occupation, years riding, and motorcycle owned will be displayed, along with other non-identifiable information that is provided by the forum including username, join date, last active, and post count will be shown.

Members are welcome to login to their account and delete any personal information at any time, with the exception of username, password, and email address as these are basic account requirements.  A forum account can be deactivated by contacting the website staff either directly on the forum by sending a PM (Personal Message) or a forum email message to user TotalMotorcycle, or by regular email using the Contact Us form in the footer on all pages across the main website.

The email address of forum members will never be shared with any third party.  The only people who have access to this information is the forum administrator and the website host for technical support purposes.  The website host is bound by this same privacy policy with relation to our member’s personal information.

## Who we share your data with

We do not collect any personally identifiable information on the main website.

We have access to personal information that you have shared with us when creating or using a forum member account.  The information you provide is never shared to third parties by us but is able to be fully viewed by members and partially shared with visitors.

## How long we retain your data

If you post in the forum as a registered member, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely.

For Members that register on our forum, we store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All Members can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot have a member profile without a username, password, and email address). Forum administrators can also see and edit that information.

Forum accounts can be deactivated if requested by the member.  Personal information including username, and email address, as well as any other required personal identifiers, will be requested from the member so the forum administrator can verify the identity of the requester and find and deactivate the correct account.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have a Member account on the forum, you can login to your account to see the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can login and erase any personal data we hold about you, except for username, password, and email address, which are basic forum account requirements. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Your data is not sent to any third parties.

## Contact information

For further information, please use our [Contact Us](https://www.totalmotorcycle.com/contactus) form in the footer on all pages across the main website.

## Additional information

### How we protect your data

We use 128-bit SSL encryption across the site.  All pages across the entire site (main website and forum) are https compliant.  Your login on the forum is protected by username and password combination, and your forum password is ciphered (a one-way hash) so that it is secure.

### What data breach procedures we have in place

The only personal data we store is the member information in our forum.  If a breach of personal data from forum member accounts occurs, we will attempt to send an email to all members (using their last updated email address) to advise them of the breach and notify them to change their passwords.  We will also post a public notice in the forum.

### What third parties we receive data from

We receive non-identifiable visitor information from our authorized advertisers and analytics providers.  This information is only used by this website for the betterment of user experience across the site, and is never sold by us to third parties.

### What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data

Our site does not perform any automated decision making or profiling with user data.

### Industry regulatory disclosure requirements

We have no industry regulatory disclosures.
